<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaitlyn Joy Mann - Web Development, Design &amp; Motion</title>
    <description>I’m Kaitlyn Mann, a front-end web developer who loves to design and create  motion graphics. Check out some of my recent projects, or read my blog.
</description>
    <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 20:10:49 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 20:10:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using PHP Variables in CSS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be nice to be able to write CSS, but use variables for commonly used elements like colors and fonts? The good news is, there is! And, it’s pretty simple too. All you need to know is a little bit of PHP, and you’re on your way to more efficient, easier to write CSS. Plus, if you need to change that color or font, you’ll only have to change it in one place instead of who knows how many…Plus, remembering &lt;em&gt;lightGold&lt;/em&gt; is much easier than remembering something like &lt;em&gt;#fceb8d&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Change your .css file to .php &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Note: Make sure you change the filename in the call to your stylesheet in your HTML as well)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Open a php block at the top of your php stylesheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php ...Your PHP code goes here... ?&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Inside the PHP block, tell the file that it’s actually a CSS document with this line of code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;header(&quot;Content-type: text/css; charset: UTF-8&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. Write your PHP variables, using the following syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$primaryColor = &quot;#666666&quot;;
$primaryFont = &quot;Raleway&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-the-variables&quot;&gt;Using the Variables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the variables you created is easy. Inside any CSS rule, where you would usually write out the color, font, or other value, replace that with the following code structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php echo $primaryColor; ?&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See a full example of this below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a {
	color: &amp;lt;?php echo $primaryColor; ?&amp;gt;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, you’re done! That’s wasn’t so bad. If you want more on using PHP in CSS, your can learn more with &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/css-variables-with-php/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from CSS Tricks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/using-php-variables-in-css</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/using-php-variables-in-css</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hosting, DNS, and Caching Issues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Switching hosting companies can be tough, especially if you want to transfer peices at a time. Specifically, I worked through transferring a WordPress install to the new hosting company, without the domain name being transferred yet. Here are some helpful tips I’ve collected as I’ve learned about hosting, DNS, caching, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-dns&quot;&gt;What is DNS?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS means domain name system. Basically, they connect web pages with their domain names. Without DNS, people would have to type in a website’s IP address to access the site. Domains make things a lot simpler. Aren’t you glad you don’t have to remember a long string of numbers just to get to Google or Facebook? Well, I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily find any website’s IP address with a command prompt. For example, in Terminal use this simple command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nslookup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow this command with a space, and the website’s url. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bohemianalps.com/blog/2007/nslookup/&quot;&gt;(Thanks to the Bohemian Blog for this info)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-challenge&quot;&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the challenge is to install wordpress on a new host, with the domain still pointing to the old website. First, you’ll back-up your WordPress installation on the  OLD server and then move it to the new server. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://codex.wordpress.org/Moving_WordPress&quot;&gt;this article from the Wordpress Codex&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issue-1-your-wordpress-install-returns-a-server-not-found-error&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1:&lt;/strong&gt; Your WordPress Install returns a Server Not Found error.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because the domain name is still pointing to your old site, and wordpress gets confused on what you’re trying to access. To fix this to work on your computer, you’ll have to edit the hosts file on your computer. Here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tekrevue.com/tip/edit-hosts-file-mac-os-x/&quot;&gt;a link&lt;/a&gt; on how to do this on a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issue-2-its-still-not-working&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s still not working…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know that your computer keeps a DNS cache for websites you’ve visited, so the edits you just made to the hosts file are actually doing nothing, until you clear your local DNS cache. Here’s a link from Apple on &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202516&quot;&gt;how to clear your DNS cache&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;issue-3-its-still-not-working&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s STILL not working…&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve completed these steps and there still seems to be issues, there is a larger problem, most likely with your hosting DNS configuration. Contact your hosting company, and see if migrating WordPress on your website without transferring the domain name will be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Luck!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/hosting-name-servers-caching-etc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/hosting-name-servers-caching-etc</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Web Design Inspiration from Line25</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/&quot;&gt;Line25&lt;/a&gt;, a blog for web creatives, has been an invaluable source of inspiration and a challenge to create better web projects. The blog mostly provides collection of helpful tutorials, resources, articles, and websites, providing inspiration and knowledge to anyone in the web industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-posts-from-line25&quot;&gt;My Favorite Posts from Line25&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far, my favorite posts from Line25 are the Sites of the Week. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/inspiration/line25-sites-of-the-week-for-july-3rd-2015&quot;&gt;this example&lt;/a&gt;, of the sites of the week of July 3rd, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekly digest of great websites captures every type of website, even websites in other languages. It’s crazy to see how I can enjoy and understand websites in other languages, just by how the site was designed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unique-ideas&quot;&gt;Unique Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these sites, I’m inspired to try new layouts and features, and break out of the routine, predictable structure of the “classic web design.” Each design is beautiful and usable in its own way, and is a constant reminder that a website does not need to look a certain way, or portray information with a certain method in order for it to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example take a look at these two websites. They are both web development companies, but their approach to their websites are very different, but both equally effective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;big-drop&quot;&gt;1. Big Drop&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio-test/img/blog-img/big-drop-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Big Drop Homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bigdropinc.com/&quot;&gt;Check out the site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lounge-lizard&quot;&gt;2. Lounge Lizard&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio-test/img/blog-img/lounge-lizard-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Lizard Homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loungelizard.com/&quot;&gt;Check out the site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-more-inspiration&quot;&gt;Want more inspiration?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/category/inspiration&quot;&gt;Line25 Inspiration Posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/inspiration/best-web-design-examples-using-parallax&quot;&gt;30 Best Web Design Examples Using Parallax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/inspiration/line25-sites-of-the-week-for-june-26th-2015&quot;&gt;Line25 Sites of the Week for June 26th 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://line25.com/inspiration/line25-sites-of-the-week-for-june-15th-2015&quot;&gt;Line25 Sites of the Week for June 19th 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/web-design-inpiration-from-line-25</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/web-design-inpiration-from-line-25</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beautiful (and Useful) Button Animations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With CSS3, we’re given endless options to animate just about anything. From buttons that fade to buttons that transform into a new shape, content that fades in to content that swings in from the side of the page. Animations can range from subtle to dramatic. As fun as it is to experiment with all of these animations, its good to remember that an animation, like web design in general, is not to entertain, or just look cool. The best animations not only are visually engaging, but meaningful as well, and help users understand why they should click on the button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-example&quot;&gt;For Example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a “next article” button could have an arrow icon emerge to the right of the button, imitating the meaning of “next” in visual space. A delete icon could empty of color, signifying content being deleted. A button reading “Add to Cart” could be replaced by a cart icon on hover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These effects are beautiful AND helpful, guiding the user through interactions on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-inspiration&quot;&gt;The Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was particularly inspired by a &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;demo showcased on codrops&lt;/a&gt;, a web design and development blog. Take a look, hovering over each button. Many of the buttons (especially in the green and purple sections) have both beauty and usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio-test/img/blog-img/creative-button-styles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Creative Button Styles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait…what about mobile? And old browsers? Hover effects just don’t work (yet) on mobile devices. While playing around with these buttons, I still have to remember to make the initial view/state of the button all the user needs to know, while the hover states provide extra, helpful, but non-essential information. But it sure would be cool if phones had hover-sensors. Think of how touches hand motions could transform the mobile web experience…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;looking-for-more&quot;&gt;Looking for More?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for more inspiration on animations, effects, and ideas for links and buttons, check out the links below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/CreativeLinkEffects/&quot;&gt;Creative Link Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/IconHoverEffects/&quot;&gt;Icon Hover Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inserthtml.com/demos/css/button-styles/&quot;&gt;Button Styles &amp;amp; Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/yoannhel/full/fHGzs/&quot;&gt;More Button Effects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/beautiful-and-useful-button-animations</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/beautiful-and-useful-button-animations</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Inbound Marketing 101</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;By the suggestion of Sonja and Aaron Dyess of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.captevrix.com/&quot;&gt;Captevrix&lt;/a&gt;, I just earned my Inbound Marketing certification through Hubspot’s free certification program. Up to that point, I’d never even heard of Inbound Marketing before. Through the training, I’ve realized the potential power behind using inbound marketing versus other marketing methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-what-is-inbound-marketing&quot;&gt;So what is inbound marketing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, have never heard of inbound marketing before, here’s a quick explanation. Instead of pushing a brand in front of potential customers, using ads, and buying email lists, Inbound marketing draws potential customers to you. How do you do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio-test/img/blog-img/inbound-marketing-101.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hubspot&#39;s Inbound Marketing Diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First&lt;/strong&gt;, through creating and distributing awesome, informational content that your customers want and are searching for. By using this method, you’re drawing the right people to your website, and offering them great content, giving you credibility, and avoiding become just another ad or piece of spam. This content can come in a variety of forms.
* Blog posts
* Infographics
* eBooks
* Whitepapers
* How-to videos
* Checklists&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second&lt;/strong&gt;, an inbound marketer continues to follow and delight prospects through the entire journey, from their first visit, to even after they become customers. They use the “inbound methodology” to attract the perfect strangers, convert these visitors to leads, customers, and finally to promoters of your product/brand. The Inbound Methodology has four stages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attract&lt;/strong&gt;: Attract strangers to your website by offering great content and distributing it through social media. Centering this content around focused keywords will help search engines find your content, and searchers find what they are searching for.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convert&lt;/strong&gt;: The goal then is to convert these visitors into leads. At the end of a blog post, for example, you can link to an offer for a free eBook download, if the visitor fills out a form with their contact information. The new lead gets free, great content, and you have a potential contact that came to you first.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close&lt;/strong&gt;: With personalized, targeting emails and other communication, you can guide leads along the journey to becoming customers. Free trials/consultations, and special offers can be used in this stage to close leads into customers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delight&lt;/strong&gt;: Once a person becomes a customer, you’re not done! Offering content that delights current customers can turn them into promoters, who will be free, credible advertising for you, attracting more strangers, and beginning the cycle once again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-more&quot;&gt;Want more?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/portfolio-test/img/blog-img/inbound-certification.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hubspot&#39;s Inbound Marketing Certifiction&quot; /&gt;
Want to learn more about Inbound Marketing? Hubspot Academy offers a &lt;a href=&quot;http://academy.hubspot.com/inbound-certification&quot;&gt;free inbound certification program&lt;/a&gt;. The program consists of 12 video classes, covering many of the topics I listed above. The videos are informational, and entertaining to watch as well. To get certified, watch the videos, and then take the online test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, you get a fun badge you can add to your LinkedIn profile, website, or share on social media. Bragging rights included. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/inbound-marketing-101</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/inbound-marketing-101</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keep Your Wordpress Site Safe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, while interning at Rock My Image, I’ve learned the importance of securing your Wordpress sites, keeping them safe from hackers, bots, and evil software. You may wonder, why would anyone want to attack a poor little Wordpress site? Well, it happens a lot, and here’s some of the ways I’ve learned to prevent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep Wordpress up to date&lt;/strong&gt;. Wordpress releases updates with the loads of bug fixes and extra security. If your site is running on the latest version of WordPress, you’ve got a solid barrier against attack.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update your plugins&lt;/strong&gt;. Similarly to updating WordPress, plugin updates address security issues found in previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking of plugins&lt;/strong&gt;, use a good security plugin. I have used iTheme Security, which comes with tons of options. You will be able to customize to your heart’s content, and sleep soundly, knowing your site is secure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete the stuff you don’t use&lt;/strong&gt;. Have any deactivated plugins or random files that you’re holding on to for no reason? Unknown files can be breeding grounds for vulnerabilities. Rip the bandaid off quick and get rid of them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why should you go to all this trouble? My site’s doing just fine, you say. Believe me, take the extra couple minutes now, and protect yourself from hours of work cleaning out a hacked site later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/keep-your-wordpress-site-safe</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://test.kaitlynjoy.com/portfolio-test/keep-your-wordpress-site-safe</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
